# **OHUMENDE PAUL OSAZE**

# Curriculum Vitae

# **BIO DATA**

Full Name: Paul Ohumende Osaze

Sex: Male

State of Origin: Edo State

Local Govt. Area: Igueben LGA

Nationality: Nigerian

**Address:** School of e-learning Project, Kampala International University, Box 20000, Ggaba Road,

Kansanga, Kampala, Uganda.

**Tel**: +234 816 525 3939, +256 708 647 935

**Email:** paul.ohumende@kiu.ac.ug mendes.paul28@gmail.com

Marital Status: Single

# **PROFILE**

A successful developer with extensive analytical and software experience of investigating and development. Multi-talented with good all round technical skills and the ability to develop and maintain close working relationships with other support and development teams. Having the personal drive required to deliver a service that exceeds the expectations of colleagues and end users through a positive, well organized and structured work ethic. Looking for a career advancement opportunity with a company that will challenge my problem solving skills and allow me to develop my knowledge & potential.

Technology is about problem solving, this is a challenge I have always loved. The potential of where the world could be with technology in 50 years' time fascinates me, and it is exciting to know that been involved allows me to move in any direction. My love for technology has made me versatile to be able to design, program and get my hands dirty with hardware problems at the same time.

# **SKILLS**

- Project Management
- Web design & development
- PHP
- JavaScript
- HTML5, CSS3
- Laravel
- Magento
- Moodle
- React.js
- WordPress
- MYSOL Database
- Mobile Application Development (Flutter & Ionic)
- Python
- Digital Marketing
- Graphic Design
- Computer repair (Hardware & Software)
- Computer Networking
- Electrical Engineering and Sound Engineering (basic knowledge)

# **INTERESTS**

- Self-development
- Data Analytics
- Programming
- Teaching
- Designing
- Surfing the internet
- Healthy conversations
- Watching cartoons
- Cooking
- Studying
- Working with hardware components

# WORK EXPERIENCE

# System Engineer / E-Learning Management System Developer

# Kampala International University, School of E-Learning Project | Feb 2020 - till date

#### **Duties:**

- Configure and setup the Learning Management System
- Load and test learning content to the Learning Management System
- Defining the roles of other E-Learning team members on the Learning Management System
- Assist in defining course objectives, scope, and sequence
- Support and monitor course functionality
- Resolve issues related to the Learning Management System courses that are reported by users
- Create, configure, test and troubleshoot online courses in the Learning Management System.
- Recommend instructional strategies, delivery media and assessment methods.
- Plan and manage development of new courseware requests
- Partnering with internal teams to produce high quality eLearning content.
- Collaborating with other members of the curriculum development and training team to brainstorm, problem-solve, and review each other's work.
- Gamification of course quiz and assignments

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Software development

# Mira Technologies Limited, Ikeja Lagos Nigeria | 2018 – Jan. 2020

#### **Duties:**

- Write well designed, testable, efficient code by using best software development practices
- Create website layout/user interface
- Integrate data from various backend-end services and databases
- Gather and refine specifications and requirements based on technical needs
- Stay plugged into emerging technologies/industry trends and apply them into operations and activities.
- Analyze user's needs, then design, test, and develop software to meet those needs.
- Recommend software upgrades for customers' existing programs and systems.
- Design each piece of the application or system and plan how the pieces will work together
- Ensure system continues to function normally through software maintenance and upgrades.
- Protects operations by keeping information confidential.

# Software Development All Saints Catholic Seminary

# Uhiele Ekpoma Edo State. Nigeria | 2018

#### **Duties:**

- Analyze the entire library system.
- Complete automation of library system solution.
- Designed and developed an online library system

# WORK EXPERIENCE

# Web development

# Mopson Pharmaceutical Limited, Ajao Estate Lagos, Nigeria | 2017 - 2018

#### **Duties:**

- Made a review on the company's website and found some flours on the preview website design.
- Identified and recommended improvements for E-mail applications & Web-page development.
- Redesigned the company's website to aid better user experience and give the company a better online representation.
- Administered the website; ensuring that the website is secure and access is limited to authorized personnel/clients only.
- Monitoring and maintaining the website and portals on a regular basis; performed updates and changes quickly and efficiently as required.

#### **Student Trainee**

# Ladoke Akintola University of Technology, Ogbomoso Oyo State, Nigeria | 2014 – 2017

#### **Duties:**

- Assist in administering & designing LANs, WANs and internet/intranet networks.
- Communicating and negotiating with users, specialists, other staff and suppliers.
- Network connectivity troubleshooting, ping, tracert, telnet.
- Responsible for communication protocols, configuration, integration & security.
- Investigating, diagnosing and resolve all network problems.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### IT Staff

# Mopson Pharmaceutical Limited, Ajao Estate Lagos, Nigeria | 2011 – 2013

#### **Duties:**

- Maintenance & management of the Critical Windows based Server Environment.
- Maintaining up to date Antivirus levels on all machines company wide.
- Troubleshooting technical problems and implementing solutions.
- Responsible for diagnosing & resolving hardware, software & end users problems.
- Acting as the first point of contact for all IT & technical queries.
- Working within a TCP/IP network environment, including DHCP, DNS, Ethernet and Provide support for LAN and WAN issues.

# PROJECTS WORKED ON

Here are some of the projects I have worked on

- Ecommerce Mobile Application
  - ➤ A mobile application that enables people to buy and make payment right from their mobile device.
- Online Library Management System
  - Online and intranet library system, with ability to periodically synchronize data. Cataloging of both physical and ebooks, with access from any device and anywhere in the world.
- School Management system
  - Automation of an entire school system which included physical and logical access control to restricted areas.
- Learning Management System
  - An online learning management system that enables people learn at their comfort and interact with instructors through a chat system and other means.

#### PROJECTS WORKED ON

- Ecommerce Website
  - A web application that enable people buy and make payment from any internet enabled device.
- Access Control System
  - A system that grants access to only authorized users to a particular physical location, using fingerprint, card, PIN, token.
- Online Payment System
  - An online system that enables users send and receive money. It interacts with the user's bank account. Money can also be transferred through a chat interface or QR code.
- Online Chat System
  - An online system that enables users chat with each other and share files.
- Company Workflow Automation
  - Automation of documents flow of a company, from production department to store, audit, sales, account department, etc.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Oshodi Senior High School Oshodi Lagos Nigeria

West African Senior School Examination | 2004 – 2010

#### NIIT Ikeja

Computer hardware and networking (CompTIA A<sup>+</sup> & N<sup>+</sup>) | 2012

#### **APTECH Ikeja**

Cisco Certified Network Administrator (CCNA) | 2013

#### Hakmub Technologies Limited Computer village Ikeja

Computer repair services | 2013

# Ladoke Akintola University of Technology Ogbomosho (Bachelor of Technology degree)

Computer Science and Engineering | 2013 – 2018

#### **CERTIFICATES**

Computer Hardware Engineering (CompTIA A<sup>+</sup>)

Computer Networking (CompTIA N<sup>+</sup>)

Google Online Marketing Challenge (semifinalist)

Google Online Marketing fundamentals

Udemy 10 hours Facebook Marketing

Udemy hour to create a WordPress website

Introduction to Data and Data Science

# **LANGUAGES**

English: Excellent speaking, writing and reading knowledge.

#### REFERENCES

Mr. Dominic Olajire – Project Manager, Mira Technologies Limited, Ikeja Lagos, Nigeria dominic@miratechnologiesng.com (+234 818 288 6545)

**Rev. Fr Julius** – ICT Director, All Saints Catholic Seminary, Ekpoma Edo, Nigeria. (+234 810 084 8362)

Engr. James Osunniyi – E-Tutor, Open and Distance Learning Center, Ladoke Akintola University of Technology Ogbomoso, Oyo State, Nigeria. jsosunniyi@lautech.edu.ng (+234 806 042 1015)

**Prof. Michael Oni** – Ex-Dean, Faculty of Pure and Applied Sciences, Ladoke Akintola University of Technology Ogbomoso, Oyo State Nigeria. omoni@lautech.edu.ng (+234 803 688 6236)

**Mr. Julius Ogunsanya** – Financial Controller Mopson Pharmaceutical Limited, Ajao Estate Lagos, Nigeria. (+234 802 734 3379)